National Federation of Music Clubs mss., ca. 1935-2007. LMC 2797
Lilly Library
National Federation of Music Clubs mss.
ca. 1935-2007
Lilly Library
National Federation of Music Clubs.
LMC 2797
3 Boxes
The National Federation of Music Clubs mss., ca. 1935-2007, consist of scrapbooks, files, minutes, correspondence, periodicals, photographs, and newspaper clippings documenting the work of the organization.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Administrative History
The National Federation of Music Clubs, founded in 1898, became an NGO member of the United Nations in 1949, and was chartered by the U.S. Congress in 1982. NFMC is a non-profit philanthropic music organization whose goal is to promote American music, performers, and composers through quality music education and supporting the highest standards of musical creativity and performance. NFMC headquarters are located in Greenwood, Indiana.
Scope and Content Note
The National Federation of Music Clubs mss., ca. 1935-2007, consist of scrapbooks, files, minutes, correspondence, periodicals, photographs, and newspaper clippings documenting the work of the organization.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Publications; III. Governance; IV. Additional.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2012
Music --United States --Societies, etc.; Music; Greenwood, Indiana; National Federation of Music Clubs --Correspondence.; National Federation of Music Clubs --History.
- I. Correspondence
  - New Members, 1957-2002, undated; 25 folders (Box 1)
  - Re: Patrillo Ban (Box 1)
  - Re: 100 years (Box 1)
  - Thank you notes (Box 1)
  - Re: Evelyn Starkey's Death (Box 1)
  - Pheobe Crookes Whaley Memorial Fund (Box 1)
  - National Music Week (Box 1)
  - Lilly Library (Box 1)
  - Dooley, Donna (Box 1)
  - Misc (Box 1)
- II. Publications
  - Newspaper clippings re: scholarships, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ruth (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, misc, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Music Clubs Magazine, 1971-1979; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - re: Death of Angeline Batista and Daisy Garton (Box 1)
  - Federation of Music Clubs State Convention programs, 1987-2000 (Box 1)
  - Federation of Music Clubs Indiana Showcase, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - Friday Musicale Calendars, 1935-1952; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1911-1970; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1970-2007; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Henley Collection Music (Box 2)
  - Friday Musicale Programs, 1944-1980s; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - History of Friday Musicale, 1906-1956 (Box 2)
  - Friday Musicale: 100 Seasons, 1906-1956 (Box 2)
- III. Governance
  - Minutes, 1963-2000, undated; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Board Minutes, 1979-2007, undated; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Indiana Federation of Music Clubs Board Minutes, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report, 1979 (Box 3)
  - By–laws– Friday Musicale and Indiana Federation of Music Clubs, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Installation and Induction ceremonies (Box 3)
  - Indiana Federation of Music Clubs Reports (Box 3)
  - Indiana Federation of Music Clubs, misc. (Box 3)
  - District Seven (Box 3)
  - Proposed Budgets (Box 3)
  - Scholarship proposals, misc. (Box 3)
  - Member lists, misc (Box 3)
  - Junior Clubs (Box 3)
- IV. Additional
  - Misc papers (Box 3)
  - Indiana Federation of Music Clubs State Convention (Box 3)
  - Ruth (Box 3)
  - Music (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook (Box 3)
  - VHS, "Friday Musicale at Meadowood", 2/13/1998 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks (5) (Box 4)